Vonnegut, Bernard; Papers ua902.068
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Arthur D. Little, 1931-1971; Undated; 3; 5.8 cubic ft.
  - Signal Corps - Case 58715, 1953-1958 (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 1)
  - Signal Corps Fog Dissipation Reports, 1953-1956 (Oversized 8)
  - Signal Corps, Photographs, Undated (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 2)
  - Southern California Air Pollution Foundation, 1954-1960 (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 3-4)
    - Southern California Air Pollution Foundation, 1954-1960
    - Southern California Air Pollution Foundation, 1954-1960
  - Spilhaus, A.F. Stony River Phenomena (Alaska 1950), 1950-1958 (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 5)
  - Steel Company of Canada, 1945-1955 (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 6-7)
  - Steel Company of Canada, 1945-1955 (Oversized 3, Folder 8)
  - Steel Company of Canada - Conference Notes, 1920-1955 (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 8)
  - Technical Papers, 1955; 1959-1960 (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 9)
  - Technical Papers, 1962 (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 10)
  - Technical Papers, 1962-1963 (Box 5 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 11)
  - Technical Papers, Undated (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 1-2)
  - Technical Proposals for Tornado Research, 1955 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 3)
  - Technical Proposal - Mapping of the Composition of the Surface and Atmosphere of Mars by an Orbiting Broadband Infared Interferometer, 1965 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 4)
  - Third Annual Conference on Atmospheric and Space Electricity, Montreaux, Switzerland, 1963 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 5)
  - Thunderstorm Experiments - Case 59667, 1956-1957 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 6)
  - Thunderstorm Experiments - Case 59667, 1956-1957 (Oversized 3, Folder 9)
  - Tornado Observations from weather Publications, 1952; 1955 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 7)
  - Tornado Photography Advertisement, 1965 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 8)
  - University of Michigan, Airplane Icing Information Course, 1953 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 9)
  - Valley Hail Suppression Association, 1954 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 10)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard "Downdrafts in Cumulus Clouds", 1954 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 11)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard "The Electrical Theory of Tornadoes", 1956 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 12)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard "Final Report - Electrical Behavior of an Airplane in a Thunderstorm", 1964 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 13)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard "Tornadoes and Thunderstorm Electricity", 1954 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 14)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard, C.B. Moore, and M. Blume "Preliminary Investigation of the Distribution of Space Charge in the Lower Atmosphere", 1956 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 15)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard and C.B. Moore "Giant Electrical Storms", 1958 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 16)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard [et.al] "Final Report - Some Atmospheric Electric Instruments for Use in Air Force Operations", 1962 (Box 6 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 17)
  - Warm Fog and Stratus Cloud Dissipation Quarterly Reports, 1955 (Box 7 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 1-2)
  - Wind Tunnel Laboratory Staff "Notes on Procedures and Analysis of Wind Tunnel Experiments on Stack Gas Dispersal", 1954 (Box 7 (3-Arthur D. Little), Folder 2)
- New Mexico, 1953-1996; Undated; 4; 1.14 cubic ft.
  Series 4 documents Dr. Vonnegut's work with the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology (NMIMT) in Socorro, New Mexico. While both were employed at Arthur D. Little, he and fellow scientist Charles Moore were invited to conduct thunderstorm research at Mt. Withington, eventually becoming part of the Langmuir Laboratory for Atmospheric Research in Socorro. Moore stayed at NMIMT, and Dr. Vonnegut moved on to the State University of New York at Albany; though their collaborative research continued for the entirety of each other's career.
  The series includes a large amount of correspondence with Charles Moore, as well as with other prominent figures related to NMIMT; Marx Brook, Stirling Colgate, and William Winn. This series also consists of data, research, and articles regarding experiments in New Mexico.
  - 215 Experiment, 1953-1987 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 1-2)
  - 215 Experiments, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 10)
  - 215 Experiments, Undated (Flat-file 3)
  - Brook, Marx, 1960-1992 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 3-4)
  - Chew, Joe "Storms above the Desert", 1985-1986 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 5)
  - Colgate, Dr. Stirling A., 1965-1985 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 6)
  - Data, 1986 (Map-tube 1)
  - Data, Undated (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 7)
  - DForest Service/ USDA, 1965; Undated (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 8)
  - Moore, Charles B. (C.B.), 1954-1996 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 9-14)
  - Moore, Charles B. (C.B.), 1954-1996 (Oversized 3, Folder 11)
  - News Articles - Lightning, 1986 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 15)
  - NMIMT, Miscellaneous, 1956-1996 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 16)
  - ONR Special Purpose Test Vehicle for Atmospheric Research (SPTVAR), 1979-1980 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 17)
  - Paper Review, Electrification of NM Thunderstorms, 1988 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 18)
  - Photographs, 1958 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 19)
  - Photographs, NMIMT, 1962-1968 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 20)
  - Reynolds, Steve, 1990 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 21)
  - Thunderstorm Electricity, Quarterly Report for period ending 7 November 1954 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 22)
  - Winn, William (W.P.), 1965-1989 (Box 1 (4-New Mexico), Folder 23)
- Tornado Research, 1837-1991; Undated; 5; 1.2 cubic ft.
  This series consists primarily of tornado observations and eyewitness accounts solicited from the general public via newspaper advertisements in areas where tornadoes and severe storms frequently occur. They are filed using the original labeling system employed by Dr. Vonnegut, where the date and place of the observation as well as a brief statement on the phenomena is used to identify the observation. Accounts of severe storms found in multiple publications, biblical references, and other historical observations are also present.
  Please note that the archivist filed all of the loose photographs together. The archivist kept any photograph accompanying observation, research, or data with that respective material.
  - ALERT, Alert Laymen's Enlistment Researching Tornadoes, 1990 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 1)
  - Barnes, Stanley L., Editor "Papers on Oklahoma Thunderstorms, April 29-30, 1970 - NOAA Technical Memorandum ERL NSSL-69, 1974 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 2)
  - Bath, Markus "An Investigation into Three Tornadoes in Sweden", 1946 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 3)
  - Biblical References, 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 4)
  - Brand, Dr. Walther "Der Kugelblitz", 1923 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 5)
  - Changnon, Jr., Stanley A. and Richard G. Semonin "A Great Tornado Disaster in Retrospect" Weatherwise, April 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 6)
  - Colgate, Stirling - Tornado Articles, 1967-1968; 1981-1982 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 7)
  - Dergarabedian, Paul and Francis Fendell "Estimation of Maximum Wind Speeds in Tornadoes", Undated (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 8)
  - Dergarabedian, Paul and Francis Fendell "Parameters Governing the Generation of Free Vortices", 1967 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 9)
  - Ellenberger, P. "And what exactly was the Cyclone of Thaba-Bosiu?", 1957 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 10)
  - Final Report "Tornado-Sferics, Season 1956" Severe Weather Planning Center, 6th Weather Squadron (Mobile), Tinker Air Force Base, Oklahoma (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 11)
  - Flora, S.D. "The Nature of Tornadoes" Weatherwise, April 1949 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 12)
  - Gannon, Robert "New scientific research may take the sting out of lightning", 1973-1974 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 13)
  - Gannon, Robert "Tornado! How science tracks down the dread twister", 1973 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 14)
  - Hare, R. "On the Causes of the Tornado, or Water Spout", 1837 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 15)
  - Historical References and Observations, 1895; 1898-1899; 1906; 1946; 1988 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 16)
  - Historical References and Observations, Undated (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 17)
  - Hoecker, Walter H. "Detailed Time-Lapse Study of the Dallas Tornado Funnel and the Attendant Debris Cloud", 1960 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 18)
  - Huff, F.A., H.W. Hiser and S.G. Bigler "Study of an Illinois Tornado Using Radar, Synoptic Weather and Field Survey Data", 1954 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 19)
  - Idso, Sherwood B. "Tornado or Dust Devil: The Enigma of Desert Whirlwinds", 1974 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 20)
  - Jones, Herbert L. "The Identification of Lightning Discharges by Sferic Characteristics", Undated (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 21)
  - Jules, Vernon "We will do something about the weather", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 22)
  - Laboratory Tornadoes, 1976 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 23)
  - Landsberg, H.E. "The Role of Atmospheric Electricity in the Atmospheric Sciences", 1974 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 24)
  - Lavan, Z. and A.A. Fejer "Luminescence in supersonic swirling flows", 1965 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 25)
  - Letter of support from Arthur D. Little to West Tulsa News on cooperation for printing Vonnegut's request for observations, 1954 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 26)
  - Letter from Harry Truman, 1957 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 27)
  - Maier, M.W. and H.W. Brandli "Simultaneous Observation of Tornado, Waterspout and Funnel Cloud", 1973 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 28)
  - Miller, Peter "Tracking Tornadoes", 1987 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 29)
  - "Notes on Certain Tornado and Squall Line Features" UAL Meteorological Circular, No. 36, April 15, 1952 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 30)
  - Observations: Adams, Mrs. J.C., Rumson, NJ "zig-zag streaks of lightning" "all hell broke loose", 1956 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 31)
  - Observations: Aiken, Mrs. Benedict D., Coconut Grove, Miami, FL "glowing with a bluish green light", 1959 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 32)
  - Observations: Anderson, Mrs. Philip, Toledo, OH, April 11, 1965 "then a great wall of white came", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 33)
  - Observations: Angus, Mrs. Florence, Toledo, OH, April 1965 "huge reddish yellow light", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 34)
  - Observations: Bauvia, Mrs. Bertha, Moville, IA "zig-zagged in its travel" "great bolt of lightning", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 35)
  - Observations: Benson, Mrs. Marcella, Toledo, OH, April 1965 "bluish white lights shooting around in the clouds", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 36)
  - Observations: Birmingham Alabama News "jagged streaks of fire resembling lightning", 1956 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 37)
  - Observations: Blomgren, Oscar, North Chicago, IL, August 1972, 1974 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 38)
  - Observations: Blumstock, Rutgers, June 22, 1928 "inside brilliantly lighted with constant flashes of lightning", 1959 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 39)
  - Observations: Bolduc, Mr. & Mrs., Castleton, NY "unknown objects in sky color of lit matches", 1977 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 40)
  - Observations: Byers, Lloyd J., Fargo, ND "luminous blue light or glow around the bottom edge of funnel", 1957-1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 41)
  - Observations: Cheyenne Tornado, July 16, 1979 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 42)
  - Observations: Cross, Marion H., Albuquerque, NM; Mississippi, 1960 "flickering pin points of light", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 43)
  - Observations: Dale, F. Douglas, Coldwater, KS "center of funnels luminous with yellow green" "balls of fire", 1960 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 44)
  - Observations: Decker, Jr., Mrs. Roy, Sparks, OK, Spring 1956 "great ball of fire was right above me", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 45)
  - Observations: Dekalb, IL, 1967 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 46)
  - Observations: Edmond, OK Tornado, May 8, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 47)
  - Observations: Elder, R.H., Suburn, AL, 1924 or 1925 "lightning constantly between tip of cone and ground", Undated (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 48)
  - Observations: Elkins, Robert E., Thorp, WI "big ball of fire and then destruction", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 49)
  - Observations: Foster, Hal, Mariana Islands, 1945 from Bulletin of American Meteorological Association, 1950 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 50)
  - Observations: Gaillard, Mary A., Mobile, AL, 1949 or 1950 "explosion with blue and green lights", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 51)
  - Observations: Godberry, Mrs. Hubert, Olney, TX, May 18, 1951 3:45 p.m. "big flash of electrical display", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 52)
  - Observations: Green, Mrs. Francis D., Ellington, CT, 1952 or 1953 "brilliant flash like brilliant lightning in the base", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 53)
  - Observations: Hamilton, Mrs. Alice, Bowers, Dallas "mass of blue and orange fire", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 54)
  - Observations: Highiet, Mrs. L.R., Toledo, OH, April 1965 "blue halo around tornado & orange balls of lightning coming out", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 55)
  - Observations: Hiser, Prof. Homer W., Miami, FL, 1959 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 56)
  - Observations: Houston, Walter Scott, Champagne, IL, Summer 1942 "searchlight beam extend out of cloud:, 1962-1963; 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 57)
  - Observations: Howland, Charles E., Formoso, KS, about 1933 & about 1952 "oppressed itchy feeling", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 58)
  - Observations: Hunter, Lee, Blackwell, OK, May 1955 "orange color fire in the center", 1956 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 59)
  - Observations: Jensen, J.C., Rock Rapids, IA, 1932 "ball lightning" Science Monthly, p. 192, 1933 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 60)
  - Observations: Johnson, D.C., Harden County, OH, May 11, 1887, 11:00 p.m. "straws blown into bark of trees", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 61)
  - Observations: Johnson, Tom, Toledo, OH, April 1965 "lights of different kinds of colors mixed up in the clouds", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 62)
  - Observations: Joliet, IL, 1990, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 63)
  - Observations: Judkins, Jr., Harold I., Rutland, MA, June 1953 "where did the lightning go all of a sudden when about 2 miles", 1956 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 64)
  - Observations: Killian, Ralph D., Spring 1927, 1962 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 65)
  - Observations: Kueck, Irma, Hickman Mills, MO, May 20, 1957 "light yellow cloud, horizontal stripes, ball of fire", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 66)
  - Observations: LeBell, C.E., Excerpts from "Mont Blanc to Everest" by Gaston Rebuffat, Undated (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 67)
  - Observations: Luke, Ray, Artist, 1924 or 1925, Oklahoma "light as day inside", 1957 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 68)
  - Observations: Lumis, Mrs. Avril H., Kansas City, KS, May 20, 1952 "yellow-white along outside of funnel as if neon lighted", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 69)
  - Observations: McCuiston, A.L., Tulsa, OK "red glow in the cloud", 1954 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 70)
  - Observations: McDevitt, Brian M., Deep Cove, Pemadumcook Lake, ME, 1975, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 71)
  - Observations: McNeese, Lee, Albany, MO, about 1907 "looked inside funnel", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 72)
  - Observations: McPherson, E.D., Dyersburg, TN, March 21, 1952 "continuous vivid lightning" "orange glow in cloud" (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 73)
  - Observations: Meabon, Herbert, Chautaugua City, NY "special lightning phenomenon", 1965 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 74)
  - Observations: Miami, FL, 1959 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 75)
  - Observations: Mississippi, 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 76)
  - Observations: Multiple States, 1963-1965 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 77)
  - Observations: Multiple States, 1968 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 78)
  - Observations: Multiple States, 1969-1990 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 79)
  - Observations: Palm Sunday Tornado, Ohio, April 11, 1965 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 80)
  - Observations: Pyle, Mrs. Kenneth, E., Toledo, OH, April 1965 "streaks of lightning in the cloud itself", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 81)
  - Observations: Peterson, Jr., Howard C., Coral Gables "pale green and then pink sheet lightning", 1959 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 82)
  - Observations: Plummer, Genevieve, St. Louis, MO "brilliant pink and flame-like flare up from horizon", 1959 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 83)
  - Observations: Pulhuj, Mrs. Paul, Toledo, OH, April 1965 "all around me was red flashing lights constantly", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 84)
  - Observations: Rankin, Frances S., Shawnee, OK, May 1, 1954 "greenish glow in center", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 85)
  - Observations: Richardson, Marvin E., Winston City, MS, 1956 "faint orange luminescence", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 86)
  - Observations: Roberts, Alpheus J., Toledo, OH, April, 1965 "surface glow", 1965-1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 87)
  - Observations: Ross, Mrs. H.L., Toledo, OH, April 1965 "it appeared to be giving off a light of its own", 1965-1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 88)
  - Observations: Schenectady, NY, June 24, 1960 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 89)
  - Observations: Setkins, William B., Northern Indiana around 1900 "Willie get under the bed" "large electrical ball of fire", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 90)
  - Observations: Shaw, William, Nevada, MO, around 1925 or 1926 "funnel grows down out of the parent cloud", 1962 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 91)
  - Observations: Shepard, L.E., Electrification of steam jets "fire balls when steam escaping from railroad engines", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 92)
  - Observations: Spiess, Lincoln Bunce, St. Louis, MO "very rapidly lightning flashing", 1959 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 93)
  - Observations: Spurr, Allan, Springfield, IL "flash reminded me of welder's arc", 1957 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 94)
  - Observations: Thompson, Mrs. J.K., Fairfax, OK, June 2, 1935 "flash more like a ball of fire" "funnel was brick red", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 95)
  - Observations: Trussell, Cliff, Joplin, MO "difference in sound of thunder in tornado cloud" "cold air coming down", 1958 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 96)
  - Observations: Veal, Mrs. Talmadge, Macon, GA "incessant shimmer of light that had no thunder preceded", 1954 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 97)
  - Observations: Vonnegut, Sr., Kurt, Indianapolis, IN, 1955 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 98)
  - Observations: Wegener, Butch, Toledo, OH, 1965 "something very bright about the size of a basketball", 1965-1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 99)
  - Observations: Willett, Myron, Oregon, OH, April 1965 "pattern in the orange like hell upside-down", 1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 100)
  - Observations: Wishnewitz, Harvey, Toledo, OH, 1965 "the place lit up just like daylight", 1965-1966 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 101)
  - Perkins, J.G. "Electromagnetism and the Tornado", 1975 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 102)
  - Photographs, 1955-1968 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 103)
  - Raco, Ronald J. "Electrically Supported Column of Liquid", 1968 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 104)
  - Reprints and copies of tornado articles, 1959-1975 (Box 1 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 105)
  - "Research on Tornado Identification" Third and Fourth Quarterly Progress Reports, Signal Corps Research, 1955 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 1)
  - "'Selective Twisters' Secret: Severity Splits Funnels" Purdue University ScienceLine, 1975 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 2)
  - Tornado Eyewitness Questionnaire, Undated (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 3)
  - "Tornado Occurrences in the United States" U.S. Dept. of Commerce Weather Bureau Technical Paper No. 20, 1952 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 4)
  - Tornado Research Airplane Flight Data, 1956 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 5)
  - Tornado Scrapbook, 1954; Undated (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 6)
  - VanderHam, C.J., "Tornado's Korte allesvervoestende wervelwinden", 1975 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 7)
  - Vaughn, Jr., Otha H., "Luminous electrical phenomena associated with nocturnal tornadoes in Huntsville, Ala., 3 April 1974", 1976 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 8)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard - Tornado Articles, 1954-1968 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 9)
  - Ward, Neil B. "The Exploration of Certain Features of Tornado Dynamics Using a Laboratory Model" NOAA Technical Memorandum ERLTM-NSSL52, 1970 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 10)
  - "Windstorm Damage Protection" National Board of Fire Underwriters Research Division, 1955 (Box 2 (5-Tornado Research), Folder 11)
- General Science Research and Inventions, 1828-1997; Undated; 6; 3.22 cubic ft.
  Series 6 contains Dr. Vonnegut's general interest and research files, as well as the inventions that he worked on throughout his career. Topics include: lightning, ball lightning, lightning strikes and the effect on aircraft, volcanic activity and storms on Mt. St. Helens and Surtsey, thunderstorm electrification, and weather-related instruments.
  A large quantity of photographs dominates the series. Please note that the archivist filed all loose photographs together. Many photographs are undated with no specifications on location or activity depicted. The archivist kept any photograph accompanying research or data with its respective material.
  - Air Force Plane Crash - England, August 28, 1976, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 1)
  - The Annals of Improbable Research, 1995; 1997 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 2)
  - "An Apparatus for Preventing the Formation and Falling of Hail" 1906 Patent Specification, 1955 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 3)
  - Art Forum, 1980 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 4)
  - Art Forum, 1980 (Oversized 3, Folder 12)
  - Articles - Multiple Topics Related to Weather, 1828; 1841; 1849; 1882; 1952-1954 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 5)
  - Articles - Multiple Topics Related to Weather, 1964; 1966; 1968; 1970-1971; 1974-1975 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 6)
  - Articles - Multiple Topics Related to Weather, 1977; 1979-1980; 1983; 1985-1987; Undated (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 7)
  - Articles - Multiple Topics Related to Weather, 1947-1948; 1958; 1960; 1964; Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 13)
  - Atlas, David and Charles B. Moore "Exploring the Weather" Lecture Notes, Undated (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 8)
  - Atmospheric Pollution Instrumentation, 1954-1956 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 9)
  - "Atmospheric radioactivity following nuclear explosions" Office of Naval Research, 1952 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 10)
  - Ball Lightning, 1959-1990 (Box 1 (6-General Science Research and Inventions), Folder 11)